Qasim Hassan Khan

0334-2638493

qasimhassankhan1991@gmail.com
http://www.templates.stillidea.net/qasim

About Me: My eight years of experience as a Front End Developer for different companies has honed my JavaScript, jQuery, Angular, Bootstrap, CSS3 and HTML5 skills, as well as my knowledge of mobile and responsive design.

My professional experience includes bringing the wireframes of the UX designer to life through HTML5 and CSS3, as well as collaborating with Back End Developers to create a stellar finished product. I think my skills and experience makes me a great fit.

I know how important the details are for a Front End Developer. My keen attention to detail and dedication to solving any problem at hand are what separates me from other candidates with similar qualifications, also I have a good hand in designing Psd web layouts as a plus that makes me an independent resource for the team .

I started my career in Multan, Pakistan and worked for multiple software houses. Now I am located & working in Lahore for more than three years. I have been also working for the international marketplace Envato (http://market.envato.com/) for more than 5 years as an author on themeforest.net (http://themeforest.net/). I have more than 60 approved items there. Visit my online portfolio in the link given at the bottom . I primarily consider myself a UI/UX developer, but I can design web layouts PSD's too as working for themeforest has taught me the typographic sense, using the eye catching colors and utilization of white spaces in the design. So, that's make me an independent UI/UX resource who can design and convert it into HTML & create interactive themes and templates by using front-end framework like Angular.

In my current role, beside development i am also responsible for my team performance, assigning tasks to the team, and reviewing their code to ensure the quality and flexible code.

Portfolio

http://www.templates.stillidea.net/qasim

Codepen:

https://codepen.io/qasimhassankhan/pens/

Religion - Islam
City - Lahore
Nationality - Pakistani
Date of Birth - 25th-March-1991
Marital Status - Married

Education:

Fauji Foundation Model School [Hyderabad, Pakistan]

Matriculation (Computers) – **72**% 2006

College of Excellence for Boys [Hyderabad, Pakistan]

Intermediate (Pre Engineering) – **58%** 2008

IMSA (Institute of Modern Sciences & Arts) [Hyderabad, Pakistan]

BCIT - 2.9 G. P

2012

Experience:

Aircod Technologies [Lahore, Pakistan]
Principal UI/UX Engineer
Dec 2019 – present

Responsibilities:

- Leading the whole Frontend team with multiple technology stack, working on multiple projects.
- Direct reporting to CEO, getting the requirements from CEO and transferring to the team with the best possible solutions.
- Training and mentoring of resources
- Detailed sessions with CEO and director to decide the layout of the application with the best possible controls and optimized results, and creating a Non Functional Frontend for the approval before delivering to the Backend Development team.
- Build reusable code and libraries for future use.
- Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability

Abacus [Lahore, Pakistan] Senior Consultant Jun 2019 – Nov 2019 (6 months)

Responsibilities:

- Designing UI/UX wireframes and designs for the government projects, get clients approval and converting those into Angular based code structure
- Designing UI/UX and bridge the gap between graphical design and technical implementation
- Develop new user-facing features
- Build reusable code and libraries for future use
- Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs
- Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability

Sublime Wireless Incorporate(SWI) [Lahore, Pakistan] Senior UI/UX Engineer Nov 2017 – June 2019 (1.5 Years)

Responsibilities:

- Translation of the UI/UX design wireframes to actual code that will produce visual elements of the application
- Designing UI/UX and bridge the gap between graphical design and technical implementation
- Develop new user-facing features
- Build reusable code and libraries for future use
- Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs
- Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability
- Paint The HTML Structure Using Provided JSON by backend developers
- Assure that all user input is validated before submitting to back-end
- Collaborate with other team members and stakeholders

Sound View Technologies [Lahore, Pakistan] Front-End Developer (Part Time) Aug 2018 – present (06 Months)

Responsibilities:

- Develop new user-facing features
- Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs
- Paint The HTML Structure Using Provided JSON by backend developers
- Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability

Systons [Multan, Pakistan] Senior Web Designer and Developer Nov 2016 – Oct 2017 (01 Year)

Responsibilities:

- Design PSD layout for themeforest.net
- Convert PSD into HTML for themeforest.net
- Train the juniors and lead the team
- Manage projects and updates

Sugotech [Multan, Pakistan] Senior Web Developer January 2013 – April 2016 (03 Year)

Responsibilities:

- Design PSD layout for themeforest.net
- Convert PSD into HTML for themeforest.net
- Train the juniors and lead the team
- Manage projects and updates

Next Syntax Technologies [Multan, Pakistan] Assistant Web Developer January 2012 – Jan 2013 (01 Year)

Responsibilities:

- Css Customization of Wordpress Website
- Perform assigned task related to CSS
- Learn new techniques

True Educators School [Hyderabad, Pakistan] Computer Lab In charge, Teacher August 2010 – August 2011 (01 Year)

Responsibilities:

- Update and maintain the computer lab
- Teaching Math and Computer
- Taking part in admin related issues

Sindh Grammar School [Hyderabad, Pakistan] Receptionist, Teacher August 2008 – August 2010 (02 Year)

August 2008 – August 2010 (02 Year)

Responsibilities:

- Front Desk Officer
- Teaching Math and Computer
- Taking part in admin related issues

Technologies:

- 1. HTML (Expert)
- 2. CSS (Expert)
- 3. PSD (Professional)
- 4. Vanilla JS/ JavaScript (Professional)
- 5. JQuery (Professional)
- 6. Ajax (Professional)
- 7. WordPress (Professional)

Frameworks:

- 1. Angular JS (Professional)
- 2. Angular 9 (Professional)
- 3. Bootstrap (Expert)
- 4. Materialize (Expert)

Tools

- 1. Photoshop CS6, CC
- 2. Visual Studio (TFS, Git)
- 3. Atom
- 4. Sublime Text
- 5. Visual studio code
- 6. Redmine

Specialties:

- 1. Pixel Perfect Coding
- 2. Ability to decide the best possible design solution based on the requirements
- 3. Well Commented Code
- 4. Super Responsiveness
- 5. Shortest Possible and flexible coding
- 6. Professional Designing Skills
- 7. Know the usage of fonts, colors and images in a design
- 8. Good Organizational Behavior
- 9. Punctual
- 10. Restricted to deadline.

Certifications:

- 1. English Language Course [Aptech, Hyderabad] [2006]
- 2. Android Development Course [The Net Rider, Multan] [2015]

Languages:

- 1. English
- 2. Urdu